89. What is beauty? Ideas of beauty are like the ocean. They change constantly, but
they're always somehow the same. There are some things that have always been considered
beautiful while other fashions come and go. Some beautiful qualities are the same across
cultures and centuries. One important aspect of beauty is symmetry. Symmetry is balance.
It refers to how alike two halves of an object are. Faces that are symmetrical are considered
more beautiful than those that aren't. Signs of good health are also always called beautiful,
such as shiny hair, clear skin, and strong teeth. Strong teeth don't necessarily have
to be white, though. In some parts of Vietnam, black teeth are considered attractive. Other
aspects of beauty change with time and geography. For example, our current obsession with thinness
in much of the world is very new. Until recently, forty or fifty years ago, it was beautiful
to be soft and round. Having some fat was considered beautiful throughout most of history.
It meant that you were healthy and didn't have to work hard. Now we know that being
fit is healthy, too. Being fit is something that takes time and effort and probably money.
Being thin now shows status the way being fat did. Different cultures have different
ideas of beauty. Some cultures in Africa and Asia value long necks. Women have their necks
stretched with metal rings to achieve a beautiful look. In ancient China, bound feet were beautiful,
though they prevented women from walking comfortably. In Renaissance Europe, high foreheads
were regarded as beautiful, so women plucked their hair lines. Some ideas of beauty change
with our opinions of health and status, but others stay the same. There are few rules
about beauty. In the end, the most beautiful person in the world is the one you look at
with love.